Guide to the Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Papers, 1963-1973 AIS.1974.03
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Papers
1965-1973
1965-1972
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Shaw, Henry F., Jr.
AIS.1974.03
8.75 Linear Feet (7 boxes)
The Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Papers are mainly comprised of 1960s and early 1970s leftist publications on topics ranging from coal miners rights, civil rights movement, communism, Angela Davis, the draft, feminism, student unrest, syndicalism, the Vietnam War, unionism, etc. Additional types of material include correspondence, speeches, and photographs.
Biography
Harry F. Shaw, Jr., was born in Grafton, Taylor County, West Virginia, in 1946. He graduated from Grafton High School in 1964 and West Virginia University circa 1968; he majored in history. Shaw died in 2005.
While a student at West Virginia, Shaw organized the Student Action Against Poverty, served as chairman of the campus Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), and was an active member of the Mountaineer Freedom Party. Among his many non-campus activities, he was the Vietnam Summer Field Secretary for West Virginia in 1967. He worked for the American Friends Service Committee as a Vietnam Volunteer and helped to organize the Southern Student Organizing Committee. He was also active in the fight for improved coal mining conditions through the Black Lung Association and Miners for Democracy.
Arrangement
The Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Papers are arranged into seven series:
Series I. Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Personal Files
Series II. Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC)
Series III. Organizations
Series IV. Subject Files
Series V. Publications
Series VI. Newspaper Clippings
Series VII. Photographs
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Scope and Content Notes
The Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Papers were assembled by Shaw while he was an undergraduate at the University of West Virginia. It is comprised primarily of 1960s to early 1970s publications of a political and social activist nature including civil rights, draft resistance, labor movements, miners and mining conditions, race relations, and the Vietnam War. The regional focal point of the collection is in West Virginia, especially the University of West Virginia, but includes materials relating to Southern, national, and international organizations. Additional materials beyond publications include correspondence, memoranda, news clippings, pamphlets, and photographs.
Photographs; Vietnam War, 1961-1975 -- Protest movements -- West Virginia -- Morgantown; West Virginia; Civil rights workers -- West Virginia -- Morgantown; Correspondence; Clippings (Information artifacts); Student protesters -- West Virginia -- Morgantown; Students -- West Virginia -- Morgantown -- Political activity; Women; Student movements -- West Virginia -- Morgantown; Ethnic groups; Labor; Social action; Politics; Labor movement -- United States; Memorandums; Pamphlets; Young Workers Liberation League; Students for a Democratic Society (U.S.); Appalachian South Folklife Center (Pipestem, W. Va.); Communist Party of the United States of America; American Friends Service Committee. Peace Education Division; Southern Student Organizing Committee (Morgantown, W. Va.); West Virginia University; Shaw, Henry F., Jr.
- Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Personal Files, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  The Harry F. Shaw, Jr. Personal Files series contains correspondence, essays, financial information, and note and appointments books related to directly to Shaw.
  - Biographical Sketches and Bus/Airline Ticket Receipts (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1966 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Includes:
    Social problems of Appalachia.
    Letters from friends covering many unrelated subjects.
    Gestation of a plan to help miners work for autonomy January 13, 1970.
    Letters to mine workers' leaders urging them to attend the meeting of the rank and file of labor scheduled for Chicago. See letter, June 2, 1970, for groups from the coal area who were expecting to attend.
    Shaw's appeal to be medically excused from the draft December 1970. Also see April 10, 1968.
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    In regard to H. Shaw's involvement in draft counseling.
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Dealing with social problems of Appalachia.
    Letter of resistance to the Selective Service from H. Shaw.
    General correspondence from friends which discuss a variety of subjects.
  - Correspondence, 1967, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Correspondence with Gene Kuhn dealing with Vietnam.
    Summer Training Institute, discussion of Appalachian social problems: organization among the miners, student labor alliances, black lung.
  - H. Shaw (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Personal Appointment Book, 1968; 1.
    - Notebook, 2.
    - Financial statements, receipt, etc., 3.
  - Essays by H. Shaw dealing with Appalachia and the draft (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC), II.
  The Southern Student Organizing Committee (SSOC) was a 1960s student activist group in the Southern United States focused on social and political concerns, including opposition to the Vietnam War and the draft, workers' rights, and civil rights. Throughout its existence the group maintained close ties to the Students for a Democratic Society (SDS). The SSOC dissolved itself in 1969. This series is primarily comprised of publication reprints from other organizations. It also includes SSOC administrative items, correspondence, financial information, news releases, newsletters, pamphlets, and leaflets.
  - Assorted materials (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - SSOC Constitution (Box 1, Item 1)
    - Pamphlet: a brief history (Box 1, Item 2)
    - Staff letter: Nos. 4, 6, and 7. (Box 1, Item 3)
    - Statement by H. Shaw on why he should be appointed to the SSOC staff (Box 1, Item 4)
    - Handbook, Spring 1969 (Box 1, Item 5)
    - Memo in regard to staff meetings, names of contact people, Phoenix mailing list. (Box 1, Item 6)
  - Worklist Mailing (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - News releases, circa 1968 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Nashville office: Vol. 1, Nos. 2-3; May 15, 1968.
    Durham office: Nos. 2, 7 8.
  - Financial reports, receipts, check stubs, bank statement (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Leaflets (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Themes: student organizing, workers' strikes, southern poverty, war, racism, draft, radical southern history, and women
  - Publications (reprints) (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - ACLU, Academic Freedom in the Public Schools", 1.
    - AFSC, "Draft Counseling Centers", 2.
    - H. Aptheker, "Negro Slave Revolts", 3.
    - Atlanta Project, "Black Power", 4.
    - Bethell, T.N., "Conspiracy in Coal", 5.
    - Black, E. & Reivich, L. "How to Select Targets to Disrupt the Empire", 6.
    - Boyte, H. "Poor Whites: On the Move", 7.
    - Brandon, P. & Park, N. "A Brief History of Duke Employees', 8.
    - Local 77, "AFSCMB, AFL-CIO", 9.
    - Brick, A. "The Campus Protest Against ROTC", 10.
    - Bruland, M. "Mississippi's Economics and Mississippi's 'New Image'?", 11.
    - Buddeberg, M. "The Student Movement in West Germany" and Cloke, K. "Japan and the Japanese Left", 12.
    - Burchill, C. S. "Chinese Aggression: Myth or Menace", 13.
  - Publications (reprints) (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Burlage, R. "The South as an Underdeveloped Country", 1.
    - "This is War?", 2.
    - Cantrel, C. & Larmon, L. "Southern Mountain Tradition," and D. T., "Folk Heroes and Protest, 3.
    - Carmichael, S. "Black Power and the Third World", 4.
    - "Power and Racism", 5.
    - Coughin, R. J. "Vietnam: An Historical Sketch from 1946 to the Present", 6.
    - Davidson, C. "The Multiversity: Crucible of the New Working Class", 7.
    - "Toward a Student Syndicalist Movement or University Reform", 8.
    - Dean, H. "Scarce Sources: The Dynamic of American [...]", 9.
    - Dellinger, O. "Cuba: The Revolution Not Seen", 10.
    - "The New Nonviolence", 11.
    - Debary, R. " Declaration at His Court Martial", 12.
    - Ferry, W. H. "Farewell to Integration", 13.
  - Publications (reprints) (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Fuentes, C. "Words for North Americans: The Arguments of Latin America", 1.
    - Genovese, E. N. "The Legacy of Slavery and the Roots of Black Nationalism", 2.
    - Glasser, I. "Judgment at Fort Jackson: The Trial of Howard Levy, M. D.", 3.
    - Goodman, P. "The Decay of American Cities", 4.
    - Guevara, C. "Message to the Tri Continental Congress", 5.
    - Hayden, T. "Student Social; Action", 6.
    - "The Power of the Dixiecrats", 7.
    - Helstein, R., Piel, G. & Theobald, R. "A Conversation--Jobs, Machines, and People", 8.
    - Henig, P., "Selective Service System or, The Man-Power Channelers", 9.
    - Jackson, B. "Our Prisons are Criminal", 10.
  - Publications (reprints) (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - JOIN (Jobs or Income Now), "Vietnam", 1.
    - Jones, M.B. "How Doc Jones Became a Case", 2.
    - Joyce, F.H. "An Analysis of American Racism", 3.
    - Kleinman, M. "High School Reform: Towards a Student Movement", 4.
    - Lamb, R. K. "Suggestion for a Study of Your Hometown", 5.
    - Lauter, P. "The Free University Movement", 6.
    - Lefin, A. "Political Meddling and the Florida Board of Regents", 7.
    - Lynd, S. "Jefferson and Radicalism", 8.
    - Millit, S. "On Revolution", 9.
    - Minnis, J. "The Care and Feeling of Power Structures", 10.
    - Moody, K. "Organizing Poor Whites", 11.
    - Mull, B. "Blue Ridge: The History of our Struggle Against Levi Strauss", 12.
  - Publications (reprints) (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - National Liberation Front, "Political Program of the South Vietnam Front for Liberation", 1.
    - Nolan, D. "The University of the Status Quo", 2.
    - "Vietnam: The Myth & Reality of American Policy", 3.
    - O'Brien, C.C. "Contemporary Forms of Imperialism", 4.
    - Ogden, A. "University Reform", 5.
    - Polack, N. "Southern Populism", 6.
    - Robbins, R. "The Future of Negro Colleges", 7.
    - Rony, V. "Davy Crockett in Little Egypt", 8.
    - Schrader, E. "Poor Whites and the Movement", 9.
    - Smedberg, M. "Duke Trustees & Labor", 10.
    - Soinit, A. "Deliberate Depopulation of Whole Areas: A Protest", 11.
    - SSOC, "Publicity Handbook", 12.
    - Stembridge, J. "Freedom School Notes" (Stembridge), 13.
    - Strauss, A.L. "Medical Ghettos", 14.
  - Publications (reprints) (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Theobald, R. "The Cybernation Revolution", 1.
    - Tornquist, E. "Over 30", 2.
    - Valentine, P. "Look out Liberals: Wallace Power Gonna Get You", 3.
    - Vanauker, "Freedom for Movement Girls Now", 4.
    - Waskow, A.I. "How to Prevent a Pogrom", 5.
    - Webb, L. "Chicago, August, 1968: to Research the Democratic Party", 6.
    - Wells, L. "American Women: Their Use and Abuse", 7.
    - Wicker, R. A. "Black Mountain College: An Experiment in Education", 8.
    - Williams, J. "Students, Labor and the South", 9.
    - Zinn, H. "Dow Shalt Not Kill", 10.
    - Zippert, J. "Rural Community Organization", 11.
- Organizations, III.
  The Organizations series contains files on several leftwing organizations including the American Friends Service Committee, anti-Vietnam War groups, Black Panthers, the North American Communist Parties and other far left political parties and committees, socialist and union groups, and Students for a Democratic Society (SDS) amongst others. Materials in this series include conference agendas and materials, correspondence, financial documents, memoranda, minutes, newsletters, publications, rally notices, reports, and speeches.
  - AFL-CIO, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Mat packers' strike of southern packing houses. Correspondence to the W. Va. SSOC asking its support for the strike, March 27, 1969. Leaflets, pamphlet, article in The Butcher Workman, February 1969. Xeroxed newspaper stories.
  - AFL-CIO publications (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Themes: job security, automation, safety, political activity.
  - West Virginia - AFL-CIO, May 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Legislative reports. Alliance of Southern Highlands financial status, May 1969.
  - AFSC, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Bulletin: "Quaker Service," No 1O7, Fall l970; No. 109, Spring, 1971. Bulletin No. 1, "Quaker Information Service."
  - AFSC publications, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - "Baltimore Civil Disorders April 1968", 1.
    - "One Day Free Universities", 2.
    - "Vietnam: The Growing Republican Dilemma," reprints, distributed by AFSC, 3.
    - "Vietnam Perspective", 4.
    - "Vietnam International," vol. 4, no. 4, 5.
  - AFSC memoranda and correspondence, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Notes from H. Shaw in regard to petitioning, leafleting, etc. H. Shaw's pay stubs.
  - AFSC committee reports, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - AFSC leaflets and pamphlets (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Themes: Vietnam, Cambodia, Biafra, draft, race relations, poverty, military. A brief history and analysis of AFSC from the Wall Street Journal, UN Declaration of Human Rights, facts and fallacies on Canadian Immigration, list and addresses of state and national Selective Service Directors.
  - AFSC - Peace Education Committee and newsletter: War/Peace Resources, April-May 1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - AFSC - Peace Education Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - H. Shaw: Background report of the reasons Shaw became Vietnam Volunteer for the AFSC, 1.
    - Correspondence in regard to Shaw's relationship with the Society of Friends, 1967-1968; 2.
    - Field reports of H. Shaw as a Vietnam Volunteer, 1967-1968; 3.
    - Correspondence with CCCO in regard to ordering draft counseling materials, 1967-1968; 4.
    - Invoices from the Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors for counseling materials, 5.
  - AFSC - Peace Education Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Biographical Sketch of A. Brick, Director, 1.
    - Minutes: PEC, 1967-1970; 2.
    - Director's Reports, 1968; 3.
    - Report to Peace and Executive Committee, September 18, 1969; 4.
  - AFSC - Peace Education Committee, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Correspondence, 1967-1969; 1.
    - Memoranda, 1969-1970; 2.
    - Leaflet in regard to the draft, 3.
    - Financial receipt, 4.
  - AFSC - Peace Education Committee - Miscellaneous reports, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Peace Education Committee, dealing with: programs for peace, draft, poverty, proposal on how to get churches involved with peace projects, Dayton, Ohio Peace Education, report by two (a couple) AFCF volunteers who spent a year in Vietnam.
  - AFSC - Peace Education Committee - H. Shaw memos, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - American Cross (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Services provided to servicemen and their families.
  - Appalachian South Folklife Center, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Statement of aims and programs; newspaper clippings; and lists of supports.
  - Black Panther Party - "History and Currant Status of the Panther Cases," by J. Dunne and S. Coleman, April 24, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Committee for Conscientious Objectors - materials for CO's, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - "On Doing Prison Time for Draft Refusal," an essay by F. P. Salstrom (revised, August 1967)
    - "Handbook for CO's", 10th ed., March 1970
  - Chicago Area Draft Resistors and Chicago Committee for Vietnam Referendum (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Clergy and Layman Concerned about Vietnam (Box 1, Folder 39)
    A brief history and analysis of statements approved by the Executive Committee. Includes leaflets and pamphlets regarding Vietnam and the draft.
  - Cleveland Area Peace Action Council and Ohio Region Mobilization Committee (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Correspondence and leaflets in regard to rallies and conferences to protest the war in Vietnam.
  - Committee to Aid American War Objectors (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Regarding immigration to Canada correspondence with H. Shaw.
  - Committee to Defend the Rights of Private First Class H. Petrick (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Regarding the right of a PFC to receive Marxist literature on base.
  - Committee to Defend Carlos Feliciano (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Regarding a Puerto Rican charged with firebombing buildings in NYC.
  - Communist Party, Canada (Box 1, Folder 44, Box 2)
    - "The 20th Convention of the Communist Party of Canada, April 4 6, 1969: Resolution, Reports, Policy Statements", 1.
    - Magnuson, B. "Unite in Struggle for Full Employment", 2.
  - Communist Party, USA - Party statements, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    Statements on: Angela Davis, 1970-1971; Black Liberation, 1969-1971; Education in Party theory/literature distribution/recruitment, 1969-1971; Fund raising appeals; House US Rep. Internal Security Committee, 1970; and the Jewish Defense League.
  - Communist Party, USA - Party statements (Box 2, Folder 46)
    Statements on: Labor, 1970-1971; Nineteenth Annual Convention; Racism/Indo China War, 1970-1971; and Women, 1971.
  - Communist Party, USA - Publications (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - "A Communist View on Chicano Liberation", 1.
    - R. Proctor, "Black Workers and the Class Struggle", 2.
    - G. Hall, "Communism, Mankind's Bright Horizon", 3.
    - H. Lumer, "Fight Against Trotskyism", 4.
    - "Indictment of Imperialism", 5.
    - "Jewish Affairs," (Periodical), v. 1 no. 1, 6.
    - "The 'Productivity' Hoax and Auto Workers' Real Needs!", 7.
    - "Russian Revolutionary Posters, 1917-1929", 8.
  - Communist Party, USA - Publications (Box 2, Folder 48)
    Leaflets, news releases, party meetings, peace information memoranda, and statements regarding party policies, practices, and goals, 1969-1971. Daily World correspondence, leaflets, pamphlets regarding circulation, 1970-1971. Also includes the publication by Halliman, M., "Discussion Guide of the 24th Congress of the CPSU."
  - Communist Party, USA - Publications (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - E. Hall, "Racism, the Nation's Most Dangerous Pollutant", 1.
    - J. North, "Socialist Cuba as Seen by a US Communist Delegation", 2.
    - "Steel Mill or Treadmill", 3.
    - "Strike in Big Steel Metal Mining, 1969", 4.
    - "Selection of Drawings from The Worker, 1924-1960", 5.
  - Council of the Southern Mountains, 1967-1970 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Correspondence - includes correspondence with H. Shaw, 1967-1970; 1.
    - Minutes of Education Commission, August 12, 1970; 2.
    - Program - Appalachian Studies Conference, October 24-25, 1970; 3.
    - Memo regarding withdrawal of OEO funds, June 2, 1970; 4.
    - Natural Resources Commission: memos and minutes, 5.
    - Essay: "Southern Appalachia a Statistical Description of a Depressed Area", 6.
    - Directory, 7.
  - Continuations Committee of the Emergency, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - Conference to Defend the Right of the Black Panther Party to Exist, 1.
    - Petitions to the United Nations to end Genocide, 2.
    - H. Shaw correspondence, 1970; 3.
  - Episcopal Peace Fellowship correspondence, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    Pamphlets, newsletter, and leaflets regarding draft, counseling, and pacifism.
  - Fellowship of Reconciliation - pamphlets, leaflets, and correspondence, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    Correspondence, pamphlets and leaflets regarding draft, Vietnam, and peace.
  - Fifth Avenue Peace Committee and the Parade for Peace in Vietnam (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Independent Socialist Clubs of America (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - J. Stein, "Perspectives: Locating the American Crisis", 1.
    - "Draft Perspective on the International Scene", 2.
    - "A Revolutionary Socialist Manifesto," written in a Polish prison., 3.
    - 1969 National Convention program, 4.
  - Individuals Against the Crime of Silence correspondence with H. Shaw, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Institute for the Study of Non-violence Journal, issues 2-3 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Jewish Peace Fellowship correspondence with H. Shaw and material regarding draft counseling (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - League for Industrial Democracy (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Newsletter - Democratic Change, 1970-1971; 1.
    - Leaflet - "The Trade Union Movement and the New South," University of Virginia, April 5-7, 1968; 2.
  - Massachusetts Political Action for Peace correspondence and pamphlets, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Milwaukee 14 Defense Committee correspondence, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Milwaukee Rank and File Action Committee leaflets and pamphlets regarding unemployment (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Mine Widows' Disaster Fund (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - National Conference for New Politics, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Credentials' Report, 1967-1968; 1.
    - Convention rules, 2.
    - Caucus list, 3.
    - Workshops, 4.
    - Correspondence with H. Shaw, 1967; 5.
    - Memoranda, 1967; 6.
    - Leaflets regarding rallies, 7.
    - Inter/Change, v 2, n. 1, 8.
    - New Politics News, v. 1, nos. 3-4, 9.
    - Resolutions of the General Convention, 10.
  - Interlocken, (Winsor, New Hampshire) - Program, objectives, and book of poems (Box 2, Folder 65)
    Described as "an international, educational community for young people interested in creative learning and adventure."
  - National Conference on the New Politics (Box 2, Folder 66)
    Caucus resolutions on: Appalachia; freedom to dissent; poverty; race relations; third party support of Vietnam; world constitutional convention; and working class.
  - National Council of State Committees on Children and Youth (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Rules of Procedure, October 27, 1965; 1.
    - "Processes of Change What State Committees Can Do," address by J. McDowell, May 9, 1967; 2.
    - Membership lists of delegates and alternates for 1968 annual meeting, 3.
    - "Principles Identified in the Youth Participation Project", May 1968; 4.
    - "Roundup" newsletter, v. 1, n. 1, 5.
    - Advisory Council on Public Welfare Report, May 9, 1967; 6.
    - Minutes for Board of Directors, 1967-1968; 7.
  - National Coordinating Committee for Trade Union Action (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Trade Union Action
    - Leaflets and pamphlets regarding mine safety unemployment and wage freeze
    - Rank & File Currents newsletter, March 1971
  - National Committee against Repressive (Box 2, Folder 69)
    Legislation; reports; memos; newsletters regarding attempts to abolish the House Internal Securities Committee; Court decisions on individual rights; and investigation of social reformers in the South by the Senate Internal securities Committee.
  - National Council of the United Campus Christian Fellowship conference proceedings, August 29 and September 3, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - National Mobilization Movement Against the War in Vietnam (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - A short history and statement of purpose, 1.
    - Summary of Administrative Committees meeting, held at Cambridge, Massachusetts, 2.
    - Correspondence to H. Shaw, 3.
    - Leaflets regarding rallies and marches, 1967-1969; 4.
    - The Mobilizer newspaper, v. 5, no. 1, 5.
  - National Organizing Committee of Hospital and Nursing Homes Employees (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - A Message from Mrs. Martin L. King, Jr., 1.
    - Union Song Sheets, 2.
    - Pamphlet: List of Objectives, 3.
  - National Strike Information Center (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Statement of Purpose, 1.
    - Newsletter #7, 2.
  - National Welfare Rights Organization, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 74)
    Leaflets and pamphlets regarding the function of NWRO and material soliciting students to help NWRO. Includes NWRO Newsletters, February-March, 1968.
  - The New University Conference (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - Pamphlet outlining goals, 1.
    - "The Student Rebellion", February 1969; 2.
    - Newsletter, v. 2, no. 1, 3.
  - North American Congress on Latin America, 1965-1968 (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - E. Black & F. Goff, "The Hanna Industrial Complex"
    - "A Study of Domination & Repression," regarding Mexico, 1968
    - U.S. Military operations in the Dominican Republic pamphlet, 1965